<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hugo on Tough Pixels Tips</title><link>https://toughpixels.com/tags/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in hugo on Tough Pixels Tips</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 20:06:44 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://toughpixels.com/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fastest Custom Hugo Setup, Copying An Empty Theme</title><link>https://toughpixels.com/tips/hugo-fastest-custom-setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 20:06:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://toughpixels.com/tips/hugo-fastest-custom-setup/</guid><description>Hugo is perfect for building extremely customized static HTML websites. If you&amp;rsquo;re learning or want to skip using a theme for any reason: here&amp;rsquo;s a trick to quickly create the files almost every Hugo site uses, and an explanation of how to use them.
Where Are The Layout Files? To make basic layout files and a new site, try this:
hugo new site project cd project hugo new theme temp cp -r themes/temp/layouts/* layouts/ rm -rf themes/temp These commands will create all the layout files you need to get started.</description></item><item><title>Loading Hugo Into Github Pages</title><link>https://toughpixels.com/tips/loading-hugo-into-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 13:45:07 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://toughpixels.com/tips/loading-hugo-into-github-pages/</guid><description>The Checklist Follow the directions on how to make a repo for Github Pages. In your Hugo project&amp;rsquo;s config.toml, make sure you include the line publishDir = &amp;quot;docs&amp;quot;. Normally Hugo generates files into a folder named &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo;, but Github Pages can only be set to look inside an child folder if that folder is named &amp;ldquo;docs&amp;rdquo;. Stay inside config.toml and make sure that your baseURL equals the URL you want to send to people to show off your site.</description></item><item><title>Fix 404 Error When Pushing Hugo to a Github Repository that Points to a Custom Domain</title><link>https://toughpixels.com/tips/fix-404-error-when-pushing-hugo-to-a-github-repository-that-points-to-a-custom-domain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 14:17:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://toughpixels.com/tips/fix-404-error-when-pushing-hugo-to-a-github-repository-that-points-to-a-custom-domain/</guid><description>The Problem You once experienced the joy of seeing your Hugo site up on github pages pointing to a custom url. Then you decided to push new pages to the repo and your custom domain is a 404 page! What&amp;rsquo;s happening??
The Solution When you update your repository&amp;rsquo;s Github Pages settings to point to a custom domain, Github creates a file CNAME inside your directory /docs. You may have accidentally overwrote this file when you did your last git push!</description></item><item><title>Making a Custom Hugo Homepage</title><link>https://toughpixels.com/tips/making-a-homepage-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 21:42:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://toughpixels.com/tips/making-a-homepage-with-hugo/</guid><description>Taking Inventory Do you know how to use the terminal? If you don&amp;rsquo;t, start here.
The first step in the installation process is noting what software is already installed. I&amp;rsquo;m running Linux (an operating system, specifically Ubuntu 18.04) and have Hugo (0.74.3) installed. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have Hugo, follow their installation instructions. With Hugo installed, run hugo new site best-website in the terminal.
Lookup Operating System Version, Lookup Hugo Version, Create Hugo New Site</description></item></channel></rss>